Ian Bogley

My passion is in understanding complex economic systems using statistics. I focus my expertise on the theoretical and practical tools necessary to make a positive impact in my community. With experience in programming languages like R, Python, and SQL, I have the resources to positively impact modern analytics teams.

Education

MASTER'S DEGREE IN APPLIED ECONOMICS | DECEMBER 2021 | UNIVERSITY OF OREGON

· Research design, machine learning (supervised and unsupervised), development and growth of nations, consumer theory, comparative statics (Classical, Keynesian, Neoclassical Synthesis, Rational Expectations), resource economics, game theory

BACHELOR'S DEGREE | JUNE 2020 | UNIVERSITY OF OREGON

- · Major: Economics, Minors: Mathematics, Business Administration
- · 3.62 GPA Overall, 3.67 GPA in Major
- **Dean's List:** Earned a GPA above 3.75 for a term while taking 15 or more credits, 3 out of the last 4 semesters.
- · Game theory, linear algebra, big data analytics, forecasting, international finance, industrial organization

Experience

- · R: Package design, forecasting (ARIMA, VAR), data cleaning, big data analysis (Google BigQuery)
- · Python: Data cleaning, web-scraping
- Politics: US Presidential Poll Errors, 2016 and 2020
- For work samples and more information, visit my website: https://ibogley.github.io/website/

Previous Roles

TREASURER | UO BRAZILLIAN JIU JITSU CLUB | SEPTEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

 Managed Club funds: worked with club sports office to ensure withdrawals/deposits were done according to University policy.

VOLUNTEER | AFFEC | AUGUST 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

· Worked with the event coordinator to document webinars and update informational email workflows and templates.

EMPLOYEE SURVEY PROJECT | SHELTERCARE | MARCH 2020 - APRIL 2020

- Submitted a one-off report to HR detailing how to use employee satisfaction survey data to improve a workplace environment.
- · Final product: https://ibogley.github.io/website/projects/survey/survey_2020.pdf

Email: ibogley@uoregon.edu
Phone: 541-829-2116
https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-bogley-857088196/
https://www.kaggle.com/ianbogley